CALLUM GILFEDDER

Software Developer

+447704647533 Callumgilf@mail.com

LINKS

Portfolio

PROFILE

Gained extensive experience with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python from my current role at Go Deploy. Diligently created over 100 polished tutorials aimed at IT professionals with a focus on software development. Skilled mathematician placing in the top 10 students on the masters programme during the first semester of year 3. Subsequently being nominated to apply for a summer school at the London Mathematics Society. Strong programming experience from both my degree and work. Experienced in many fields of mathematics with strengths in applied, pure and computational mathematics. You can view my portfolio from the link above.

HTML Beginner React CSS Beginner Django JavaScript Git and GitHub Python Advanced Analytical Thinking Skills

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

♣ Cloud Specialist, Go Deploy
Sep 2021 — Present
Milton Keynes

Gained experience in front-end web development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and I am currently working on the basics of React. Greatly developed my experience with Python as well as learning the basics of Django. Overall my role at Go Deploy was to create tutorials that were sold to customers wanting to expand their tech knowledge. Even though my role title was cloud specialist I was given great freedom to choose the topics we created tutorials about, so I was initially trained in Azure but then turned my focus towards creating full length courses teaching software development. Courses created at an intermediate level included: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python. Courses created at introductory level included: React, Django, R, Go, Pandas (Python Library), PostgreSQL. This lead to an understanding and practical application of all of the mentioned languages and frameworks. Created over 100 high quality tutorials and managed the upkeep of hundreds more, this provided the company with a huge batch of new exemplary tutorials for their website.

❖ Waiter, China Rose May 2014 − Aug 2014 − Doncaster

Waited tables for a high end Chinese restaurant. Served as a friendly, hardworking, and punctual employee. Working here led to the following needs and growth:

- Developed customer service skills.
- High stress environment requiring the ability to remain calm under pressure.
- Adapted to the needs of the customer.

♣ Leaflet Distribution, Hayfield Academy Jul 2014 — Jul 2016

Summer job delivering evening class leaflets to a wide area of Doncaster. This required careful pre-planning of delivery routes that was handled independently. Worked with a strong attention to detail and excellent record-keeping abilities. This developed and required:

Doncaster

- Planning and organizational abilities.
- Independence and initiative.
- Discipline to handle the long days on feet.

EDUCATION

♣ University Of Leeds
Degree: Integrated Master's and Bsc (Hons) of Mathematics
Aug 2017 — Aug 2021
Leeds

<u>Bachelors Dissertation</u>: Computational Applied Mathematics.

• Successfully analysed the efficacy of computational methods for a multitude of applied problems. This is a highly transferable skill that can be applied to many professional practices.

Master's Dissertation: Periodic solutions of the N-body problem.

- Independently developed a computational technique for measuring a quantity of vital importance to my
 topic that I then optimized twice. Improving it's performance by a factor of 1000-10000% depending on the
 circumstances.
- Numerically simulated solar system dynamics for long-term stability forecasting and extrapolation.
 Displaying considerable ability in dealing with exceedingly complicated topics with a rigorous and scientific attention to detail.

<u>Modules Included</u>: General Relativity. Entropy. Linear and Non-linear Waves. Advanced Mathematical Methods. Statistics. Logic. Financial Mathematics 1 - 3. Analysis. Topology and Geometry. Computational Mathematics.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Manchester and Hull Marathon's
Apr 2018 — Apr 2018
Manchester

Raised approximately £300 each for Cancer Research UK and the Batten Disease Family Association while independently organizing the advertising for donations. Exhibited excellent self-discipline and self-management skills. Rigorously planned training regiment and stuck to it diligently. Then successfully completed the difficult task that is a marathon. With the fastest time being around 4 and a half hours.

❖ Youtube Channel Jan 2014 — Jul 2017

Doncaster

Created a You-tube channel that gathered a community of around 300 people viewing the content on a regular basis. With videos attaining up to a couple thousand views. This skills I developed during this time were:

- Clean and professional digital art and design skills, that was used to create strong thumbnails that would intrigue the viewer to click onto the video.
- Gained experience with several video editing software, and successfully edited the videos to a highly professional and aesthetic standard.
- Developed speaking and communication skills that were required to entertain the audience who viewed the
 videos, and entertained/communicated with the audience leading to at least 300 people subscribed to the
 content.

HOBBIES

Exercise and fitness. Weightlifting. Creating, editing and publishing videos. Piano playing. Physics and cosmology. Avid reader of philosophy, specifically metaphysics, epistemology and ethics. Badminton and tennis.